http://www.ask.com/privacy

Ask Media Group Privacy Policy
Last Updated On: September 10 2020
Introduction and Scope
Information We Collect, How We Use It, and How and Why We Share It
More Details On Information Collected, Purpose of and Basis for Collection
Additional information about Sharing with Third Parties
Your Opt Out Rights and Choices
For California users: Opt out of sharing for Interest Based Advertising (“Do Not
Sell”)
1) INTRODUCTION AND SCOPE
AMG Sites. Ask Media Group LLC, (“AMG”), directly or indirectly operates a number of search and
everyday useful content sites including Ask.com, Reference.com, Consumersearch.com, Smarter.com, Life123.com,
Shop411.com, and many other sites (click here for more info about AMG).
We understand that your privacy is important to you, and we are committed to being transparent about the information
we collect and process upon your use of our websites. This Privacy Policy describes our practices concerning the
personal information collected, processed and stored by AMG when you visit and use websites operated by AMG
as well as the any homepage browser extension for Chrome, Firefox and Edge offered by AMG that enable access to these sites (“Sites”).
If you are accessing a different version of the Ask.com site via an Ask.com branded browser extension,
toolbar or other browser application, you are using a service offered by AMG’s affiliated business Ask Applications
and this privacy policy is applicable.
California Based Business. AMG operates the Sites from California in the United States of America
and, regardless of your place of residence or access location, your use of the Sites is governed by the laws of the
State of California. Users who access or use the Sites from other locations consent to the transfer and processing
of their data in the United States of America and any other jurisdiction throughout the world. This Privacy Policy
is provided in English. Translations to certain other languages may be available and can be requested by contacting
us here.
User Consent and Age Requirement. By using the Sites, you consent to our collection and use of your
information as described in this Privacy Policy. Information about our use of cookies and how you can change your
cookie settings can be found here. Our Sites are intended for general audiences over the age of 16 years old. We do
not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 16 years old. We may promote certain content to a
younger audience for certain sites in the United States. IF YOU ARE NOT AT LEAST 13 YEARS OLD IN THE UNITED STATES
OR 16 YEARS OLD IN OTHER COUNTRIES, DO NOT USE THE SERVICES.
2) Information We Collect, How We Use It, and How and Why We Share It
This section will serve as the notice at collection as provided in Section 1798.100(b) of the California Consumer
Privacy Act.
Access to web search results or other general content on our Sites or installation of a browser extension does not require you to create an account. You can
visit and use our Sites without providing us any identification (e.g., name, date of birth), contact (e.g., email
address, phone number) and/or account (username and password) information.
The chart below describes what data we collect that qualifies as “Personal Information” in California or “Personal
Data” in the European Economic Area, how we collect or access it, how we use it, with which third parties we share
it, and the purpose for sharing. In addition, we may collect, use and disclose your personal information as required
or permitted by applicable law, as directed by you, or in accordance with this Privacy Policy (See Section 3 below for more details).
We only permit third parties to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our
agreements with them. Our service providers with whom we share your data may also engage vendors to help them
process user data, so they can provide their services to us.
Categories of Personal Information
How we collect it
How we use it
Who we share it with
Purpose for sharing
Your IP address
We automatically collect the IP address you use each time you visit our Sites. We get this information from
your browser when it interacts with our servers.
We log these IP addresses in our user visit logs.
This is to determine what country or state or province you are in to show you relevant search results,
content, and ads. This is also to analyse fraudulent traffic patterns. We also analyse which regions of the
world our users come from so we can develop search and content offerings for these regions.
We share IP address, and your Site activities tied to your Unique ID with vendors who help
us operate our Sites by providing the following services:
Site hosting and database warehousing
Content delivery from our servers to your device
Advertising inventory management and operations
Service features and functionalities such as video players, browser notifications, social media
sharing, subscribing to email newsletters or posting comments
Business and technical performance analytics
Security
Your data may also incidentally be shared with vendors for IT support, data backup and recovery service, and
office software.
We also share this data with our parent company IAC for security purposes. IAC analyses all traffic patterns
from all IAC group companies for site security and fraud prevention.
These vendors process our user's personal information to:
Provide their services to us and determining what amounts are owed to them based on traffic volumes
or other metrics
Logging page impressions and user actions for their business analytics
Detecting and addressing fraudulent behavior or illegal activity on their service
Monitoring the proper functioning of their services, quality assurance, finding errors and fixing
them
Internal research
Improving on their products and services
A unique ID assigned to your browser
We attribute a unique ID to your browser for each of the Sites that you visit (Browser ID). We store this
information in a cookie set on your browser. See our Cookie Policy for
more information on cookies.
Every time you visit the same Site with the same browser, we recognize you as the same visitor through
your Browser ID. If you use a different device or a different browser, or if you visit a different Site
with the same browser, you will be identified as a different user with a different Browser ID.
This is only so we can count unique users and repeat users for each of our Sites. We can determine which
of our Sites receive more repeat visits and which type of content causes users to come back to the
Sites.
We do not use your unique ID to assign you to an “interest segment” for marketing or
advertising, nor to target ads to you based on the searches you made, content you viewed or pages that
you clicked on and visited.
Your activities on our Sites
All of your actions on each of our Sites with the same browser (your visits, search queries, search results
you click on, URL of the webpage you were last visiting before clicking to our Site, pages viewed, any installation of a browser extension, comments
posted-where applicable, duration of visit) are tied to the Browser ID of that browser for that Site. Your
browser has a different Browser ID for each of our Sites and so your actions on one of our Sites are not
tied to your actions on any other Site.
This is to count search queries, clicks, page views, repeat visits, time on site and other metrics so we
can determine which search queries are trending, which content, web page layouts or user interface are
the most popular or generates the most revenues.
This is also to determine payments owed to content and advertising partners, as well as marketing
agencies.
If you install a browser extension, an installation ID will be created and tied to your Browser ID.
Other technical information
As you interact with the Sites, we may collect additional technical information via automated means:
Information about your computer or mobile device such as type of device, mobile device ID number,
screen resolution, web browser information and operating system or platform
Your browser preferences and settings (time zone, language, etc.)
This information is also tied to your Browser ID.
This is to present to you search results and content in your preferred language and present our Site pages
in a format that best fits your device screen and format.
Email address you may submit
Some of our Sites may allow you to subscribe to daily, weekly or monthly email communications from us. If
you decide to subscribe, you provide your email address to us. Your email address will not be tied to any
Browser ID and therefore will not be tied to any of your other activities on our Sites.
We use your email address only to send you our own email communications. You can unsubscribe at anytime
using the links in the footer of the email or via our HelpDesk.
We share your email address with vendors who collect email addresses and send emails to our subscribers on
our behalf. When you interact with an email message that you receive from us, they may collect information
about your device and whether you opened, read, deleted the email, or took any action promoted by the email.
We do not sell your email address to any third party.
Contact information you may submit via our HelpDesk
When you fill out a form to contact us via our HelpDesk, we retain your email and any other
information you provide.* We do not combine this information with any of your activity data and keep it in a
separate database.
This is used only to respond to your HelpDesk
request. We do not use your contact information for any other purpose.
There is no need to provide to us (and we strongly discourage you from) providing any personally
identifiable or sensitive information about you or anyone else such as your exact location, physical
address, telephone number, health, race, religious beliefs, or sexual orientation.
Our HelpDesk platform is powered by Zendesk. Your
information is hosted by Zendesk.
Professional or employment information and education records
You may submit professional and education information about you when you submit a job application to us. We
do not combine this information with any of your activity data and keep it in a separate database.
This is used only to respond to your job application and to retain your information to contact you in case a
future job opening corresponds to your qualifications.
Our job application platform is powered by Greenhouse.
Your information is hosted by
Greenhouse.
The chart below describes what data may be automatically collected by third parties when you visit our Sites via code
that we implement to our Sites to allow them to access your browser. In certain cases these third parties are
co-controllers of personal data with us. We only permit such third parties to collect and process your personal data
in accordance with our agreements with them.
Categories of Personal Information
How third parties collect it
Which Partners collects it
How they use it
IP address and cookie data collected by social media platforms
Social media features that we implement in the Sites (like the Facebook “Like” or “Share” button) may allow
the social media providers to collect your IP address and the URL of the page of the Site you are on when
you use the feature. The sharing features may also set a social media service cookie to your browser.
Social Media Platforms
Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the social sharing platform that
you agreed to upon creating your account with them.
IP address collected by third parties and third party cookies
We implement on our Sites certain code provided by our advertising partners that enable them to:
Collect the IP address that you use when you visit our Sites
place or recognize a cookie on your browser or other tracking device (for example, tied to your
mobile device ID).
This happens when we implement software code on our Site pages that allows our partners to interact with
your browser, such as a pixel or beacon.
Content partners who provide content or search targeted or contextually targeted ads on our Sites.
Agencies who place ads on third party sites to promote our Sites.
Publisher networks (such as Facebook or Google) on which we or our agencies place advertisements to
promote our Sites
This is so they can:
Provide their services to us
Determine payments owed to them
Analyze fraudulent traffic patterns
Detecting and fixing errors in their service
Internal research and improving their service, including to increase their revenues
Internet usage data collected via cookies
Certain partners use cookies or tracking devices that enable them to:
recognize your browser or mobile device when you visit our Sites and other sites
collect information about your internet usage across multiple websites, including your visits to
and actions on our Sites
Such information collection and use by third parties via cookies and tracking devices only occurs
with your consent where required (such as in the European Economic Area). It may qualify as a “sale”
of personal information under the California Consumer Privacy Act. For more information and
how to opt out of any such “sale”, see Opt out of sharing for Interest Based
Advertising in Section 5 below.
Advertisers and digital advertising technology intermediaries who place interest based advertisements on our
Sites.
They use tracking devices to place ads on our Sites targeted to you based on your past actions on our Site
or on other sites (interest based targeting)
To deliver relevant search results to you, we may use third party services, such as YouTube for video results.
If you watch a video sourced from YouTube embedded in our search results page, then your use of the YouTube service is
subject to the YouTube Terms of Service and the Google Privacy Policy.
Third-parties who provide us with products and services may also place cookies, ad tags and/or beacons that collect
the information outlined above in order to provide us with products and services including analytics tools (e.g., Google
Analytics) allowing us to analyze the performance of our Services and advertisers and ad networks allowing
the delivery of targeted advertisements. These third parties may also collect information about you from other
sources and combine it with other information collected about you from third party websites not affiliated with us.
For example, advertiser and advertising networks, as well as data analytics companies who service them, may
participate in interest based advertising and track your activity across various sites and/or devices where they
display ads and record your activities, so they can show ads that they consider relevant to you. Where necessary, we
will obtain your consent for these activities.
3) More Details On Information Collected, Purpose of and Basis for Collection
Technical information. As you interact with the Sites, we may collect additional technical
information via automated means:
Information about your computer or mobile device such as type of device, mobile device ID number, screen
resolution, web browser information and operating system or platform
Your browser preferences and settings (time zone, language, etc.)
Internet provider or mobile service provider name
This information is also tied to your Browser ID.
Aggregated user information. We routinely aggregate the personal information of all of our users
into user usage statistics for our Sites. With this aggregation, your personal data is mixed with other user data
and becomes de-identified. We are not able to identify or re-identify you or any particular user. We do not treat
de-identified data or aggregate consumer information as personal information and we reserve the right to convert, or
permit others to convert, your personal information into deidentified data or aggregate consumer information.
Sharing de-identified aggregate data with third parties does not constitute a sale or transfer of personal
information.
Legal basis for collection. We collect and use your personal information on the grounds of the legal
basis described below:
Provide our services: we process your personal information to provide our web search and content services.
This is so we can comply with our contractual obligations to you.
Improving our services: we analyze information about how you use our Sites to provide an improved experience
for our users, including product testing and site analytics. It is in our legitimate business interests to
use the information provided to us for this purpose, so we can understand any issues with our Sites and
improve them.
Compensating our partners: we process your personal information for purposes of calculating compensation to
be paid to our third party product/service providers and distributors and to analyze usage across products,
services and distribution partner/channel. It is in our legitimate interest to appropriately determine
amounts to be paid to our partners and inform our product roadmap and distribution strategy.
Communicating with you: we may use your personal information when we communicate with you, for example if we
are providing information about changes to the terms and conditions or if you contact us with questions. It
is in our legitimate interests that we are able to provide you with appropriate responses and provide you
with notices about our Sites and services.
Marketing: we may use your personal information to deliver relevant advertisements to you to promote our
Sites, and measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. It is in our legitimate interest to analyze
the interests of our users to craft more relevant advertising messages and inform our marketing strategy. We
may use automated decision-making to deliver tailored advertisements based on your personal information. In
most cases, we use cookies and trackers placed on your browsers by our marketing network partners, such as
Facebook.
Exercising our rights: we may use your personal information to exercise our legal rights where it is
necessary to do so; for example, to detect, prevent and respond to fraud claims, intellectual property
infringement claims or violations of law or our Terms of Service.
Complying with our obligations: we may process your personal information to, for example, carry out fraud
prevention checks or comply with other legal or regulatory requirements, where this is explicitly required
by law, such as responding to your request for data access or deletion.
Customizing your experience, including ads: when you use the Sites, we may use information about your use of
the Sites (queries you submitted, content you viewed) to customize your experience, such as by providing
personalized elements and showing you content based on your recent interests. We may use automated
decision-making for these activities. Upon your affirmative consent or request, we may use your browser
information to send you notifications about content on our site via your browser. As required by applicable
data protection and privacy laws, we will obtain your consent for these activities or enable you to opt out
of these activities.
Third party links. The Sites include many links to third-party websites, services, widgets, ads, and
other services. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share
data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy practices.
4) Additional information about Sharing with Third Parties
In addition to the sharing described in the chart above, we share your information with third parties for the
purposes described below:
Group Companies: We share de-identified search query data with Ask Applications to help them improve their
products and services.
Fraud prevention: we may disclose your information to third parties when we believe disclosure is necessary
to investigate, prevent, or respond to suspected illegal or fraudulent activity or to protect the safety,
rights, or property of us, our users, or others.
Law enforcement purposes and public safety: if requested or required by government authorities, such as law
enforcement authorities, courts, or regulators, or otherwise to comply with the law, we may disclose any
information we have about our users. We may disclose information collected about you in order to exercise or
protect legal rights or defend against legal claims. We also may be required to disclose an individual’s
personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national
security or law enforcement requirements.
Sale or merger of our business: we may transfer your information to a third party if we or any of our
affiliates are involved in a corporate restructuring (e.g., a sale, merger, or other transfer of assets).
5) Your Opt Out Rights and Choices
You have rights and choices regarding our collection and use of your personal information, as well as the collection
and use of some of our third party partners. A few of those choices are set forth below and others are described in
our Cookie Policy.
Removing our cookie. If you remove our Browser ID cookie from your browser cache, we will no longer
recognize your browser and activities until a new cookie is placed. Any future site activities you perform after you
delete this cookie will not be tied to your previous activities which were associated with the removed cookie.
Removing Interest based advertising cookies. You can opt-out of third-party interest-based,
advertising-related cookies, pixel tags and web beacons, to prevent our advertising partners to deliver targeted
interest based ads to you. You can choose to opt-out through these (and other) resources:
Network Advertising Initiative (http://www.networkadvertising.org/)
Digital Advertising Alliance (http://www.aboutads.info/consumers)
Your Online Choices (http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)
You will continue to see advertisements on our Sites, but they will not be tailored to you based on any past
behavior on our Sites or other websites. You may, however, still receive customized content and/or ads based on the
search queries you submitted or the content of the pages you are visiting.
Removing Interest-based advertising from Mobile Tracking Devices. You may opt out of tracking and
receiving tailored advertisements on your mobile device by some mobile advertising companies and other similar
entities by downloading the App Choices app at https://youradchoices.com/appchoices
Other Privacy Tools. In addition, third party tools enable you to search for and opt-out of some of
these devices, such as the Ghostery browser plug-in available at https://www.ghostery.com/.
Do Not Track. Do Not Track (DNT) is an optional browser setting that allows you to express your
preferences regarding tracking by advertisers and other third-parties. However, we do not recognize or respond to
browser-initiated DNT signals, as the Internet industry is currently still working toward defining exactly what DNT
means, what it means to comply with DNT, and a common approach to responding to DNT.
For California users: Opt out of sharing for Interest Based Advertising (“Do Not
Sell”).
There is no industry consensus on whether enabling third parties to collect personal data via cookies for interest
based targeting is a “sale” under California Consumer Privacy Act. We however want to give you choices regarding
third parties using cookies or tracking devices to collect information about your internet usage while you visit our
Sites (see the second chart in Section 2 above for more details on these practices).
Some browsers have signals that may be characterized as Do Not Sell signals, but we do not understand them to operate
in that manner or to indicate a do not sell expression by you, so we currently do not recognize these as a do not
sell request. We understand that various parties are developing do not sell signals and we may recognize certain
such signals if we conclude such a program is appropriate.
If you do not wish for our advertising partners to collect your personal information for interest based advertising
purposes, click the button below to “Opt Out”. As an alternative way to exercise your Opt Out right, you may contact
us via our HelpDesk and we can provide further instructions on
how to use the Opt Out button below. We manage Opt Out requests on a per browser basis, using your Browser ID
cookie. This means that we need access to your browser when you click on the Opt Out button below in order to
respond to your Opt Out request. We therefore cannot process any Opt Out request from a third party acting as your
agent.
Opt Out of Third Party Sharing for Interest Based
Advertising
This function is not activated if you do not have a California IP address. If the button is not
active, please try again from a California location.
You have opted out of third party sharing by Ask.com for interest based advertising. We will no longer
allow our advertising partners to use the personal information gathered from your browser’s activities for
interest based targeting to you across various websites and services. However, while we do our best to
contractually restrict our advertising partners, we do not always have the means to verify or audit their
compliance with your opt out request because we do not have access to their data processing systems.
Our advertising partners will also be allowed to set or recognize a
cookie on your browser only to provide services to us. This means that the personal information tied to your
browser may still be used by our advertising partners to help us perform advertising-related functions such as
measuring, reporting and optimizing the effectiveness of our ads, capping how many times you may see an ad,
counting ad impressions and user actions taken after clicking on an ad, ensuring services are working correctly
and securely, providing aggregate statistics and analytics, or reducing ad fraud.
You are not opted out of all interest based advertising, as some of our advertising partners may still target ads
to you based on information they collected about you prior to you opting out. If you would like more information
about how to opt out from interest based advertising from multiple websites and services, please visit http://optout.aboutads.info/#/ and http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#. You may also
download the AppChoices app at http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices to opt out in mobile apps.
We manage your Opt Out status via your Browser ID cookie which applies to this Site only (see chart in Section 2 above). This means that if you delete cookies from your browser or visit this Site
from another browser or device, we will not recognize you as an Opted Out user. You will need to click on the
Opt Out button from those other devices or browsers to effect the Opt Out for those devices or browsers.
Similarly, if you visit another Ask Media Group Site, you will need to Opt Out via the Opt Out button located on
the Privacy Policy page of that Site to effect the opt out for that Site.
6) Your Access, Revision & Deletion Rights
Right to know/right of access
If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA) or in California, or in certain other states, you have
specific rights to know and have access to the personal information that has been collected and stored by the web
properties that you visit (and in the EEA, right to correct such information). Your rights can only be exercised if
such web properties can adequately verify that you are the same person as the user whose data is being requested. At
Ask Media Group, we do not collect sufficient data to authenticate any particular user. As indicated in Section 2 above, we only recognize a unique browser based on the Browser ID we assign to that
browser for a particular Site. A Browser ID could therefore correspond to multiple individuals. In the same way, one
user could have multiple unique browser IDs if they visit multiple Sites or visit the same Sites with multiple
devices or browsers. Since the personal information we collect related to a Browser ID is not sufficient to verify
that the corresponding browser belongs to the person making the request, we are not able to provide any information
in response to any request to know or access specific personal information about a user. This is to prevent anyone from
using your browser to obtain your search or browsing history. We want to make sure your search and browsing history
does not fall into the wrong hands.
However, upon your request, and provided you are able to provide to us your Browser ID, then we may provide you with
the following information collected within the last 12 months:
Which categories of personal information we have collected about you (based on your Browser ID or other
information you have provided to us), and how we collected that information, as well as the business or
commercial purposes for our collecting such personal information.
A list of the categories of personal information shared with third parties for a business purpose and the
categories of third parties to whom we have shared your personal information.
A list of categories of personal information that may have been collected by third parties when you visited
our Site, and the categories of third parties who may have collected such information.
Information relating to your Browser ID is retained by us for various time periods, so we may not be able to provide
information for the full 12 months preceding your request.
Please note that if you have provided to us your email address, or have submitted a HelpDesk request, or have submitted a job application with
us, your contact information will not be tied to your Browser ID and we will not be able to verify that any Browser
ID information corresponds to any additional information you provide to us. See below for requests regarding
additional information you submit.
Right to delete
If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA) or in California, or in certain other states, you have
specific rights to request us to delete any personal information we have stored about you. In the EEA, you also have
the right to withdraw any consent that you have previously provided to us to store or use your personal information.
As indicated above, since all personal information we have is tied to your Browser ID, we are only able to delete
your personal information from our databases if you can provide to us that Browser ID. You can also request deletion
of certain other information that is not tied to your Browser ID as further described below.
Process to submit a right to know/right of access or right to delete request
To request us to access personal information categories or delete personal information we have collected with
respect to your Browser ID, please follow these steps:
Click on the Browser ID button below to get your Browser ID and copy your Browser ID to a safe place so you
can later send it to us. Remember that this Browser ID is unique to this website. If you visit a
different Site with the same browser, you will be identified as a different user with a different
Browser ID.
Browser ID
FF5F646D-4320-4FDF-AC67-C57D16DDA7D5
Contact us via our HelpDesk, click the “Contact Us”
button, then fill out the form. Select “Request access to or deletion of your personal data” in the
drop-down for the Subject field.
Provide your Browser ID number
Provide a written and signed statement confirming that:
You are a resident of California, or a country in the EEA (please indicate which country) or another
state where the laws provide you similar rights (please indicate which state)
You are the rightful owner of the browser that corresponds to the Browser ID you are providing; and
you are the sole user of that browser and no other individual has used the browser
Clarify whether you are requesting us to (a) delete all of the personal information tied to your Browser ID;
or (b) send to you information on the categories of personal data we have collected and shared that are tied
to your Browser ID.
To assist us in processing your request in a timely manner, please make your request in English if you are
able to do so.
We manage requests to delete or access personal information on a per Browser ID basis, which is the only way we have
of recognizing or authenticating a user. This means that we need access to your browser when you click on the
Browser ID button above and will process your request based on that Browser ID. We therefore cannot process any
request from a third party acting as your agent.
All requests for access or deletion will be reviewed by our legal and compliance team and we reserve the right, in
compliance with applicable laws, to accept or reject, or make further inquiries regarding, any requests. We try to
respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request
is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you
updated. We will typically not charge a fee to fully respond to your requests; provided, however, that we may charge
a reasonable fee, or refuse to act upon a request, if it is excessive, repetitive, unfounded or overly burdensome.
If we determine that the request warrants a fee, or that we may refuse it, we will give you notice explaining why we
made that decision. You will be provided a cost estimate and the opportunity to accept such fees before we will
charge you for responding to your request.
Unsubscribe and deletion of email information
To stop receiving email communications from us, you can opt out by using the unsubscribe mechanism in the email you
receive, or by contacting us via our HelpDesk and requesting
us to no longer receive emails from us. Note that regardless of your email preference settings, we may send you
transactional and administrative messages regarding our Sites and services.
If you have provided your email address to us by subscribing to one of our Sites’ email communications, you may
request us to remove your email from our database by contacting us via our HelpDesk. Note that your email is not tied to your Browser ID
and so deleting your email will not automatically delete from our systems all personal information we have relating
to your activities on our Sites. See Section 2 for more details on Browser ID related personal
information.
Deletion of information you submit via our HelpDesk
You may request us to delete all the information you submitted to us via our HelpDesk by contacting us via our HelpDesk. However, we
reserve the right to retain any information you provided via our HelpDesk in order to defend legal claims, retain a
record of our compliance with laws, including privacy and data protection laws, and other statutory data retention
requirements. Note that except when you provide your Browser ID via a HelpDesk request, your HelpDesk request
information is not tied to your Browser ID. Deleting your HelpDesk request information will not automatically delete
from our systems all personal information we have relating to your activities on our Sites and you must make these
requests separately. See Section 2 for more details on Browser ID related personal information.
Deletion of information you submit in response to a job posting
You may request us to delete all the information you submitted to us in response to a job posting by contacting us
via our HelpDesk. However, we reserve the right to retain any
information you provided to us to apply for a position at Ask Media Group in order to defend legal claims, retain a
record of our compliance with laws, and other statutory data retention requirements. Note that your job application
information is not tied to your Browser ID and so deleting your job application information will not automatically
delete from our systems all personal information we have relating to your activities on our Sites. See Section 2 for more details on Browser ID-related personal information.
7) Data Hosted in the United States
Ask Media Group is headquartered in California, and in order to access our Sites,
your browser interacts directly with our Site servers in the United States.
By visiting or using our Sites, your data is automatically collected, processed and stored on servers located in the United States.
If you are located in the United Kingdom (“UK”), Switzerland, or the European Economic Area (“EEA”),
this means your data is stored in a country the laws of which may offer less personal data protection than your country.
We however comply with requirements set forth in the EU General Data Protection Regulation when we process your data,
and you have the right to lodge a complaint with the data supervisory authority of your country if you feel that we
have unlawfully processed your data.
Your personal data is also processed in the United States by some of the third parties with whom we share your data, as detailed in the chart in the
Information We Collect, How We Use It, and How and Why We Share It
Section above and in the Additional information about Sharing with Third Parties
section above. We have entered into data processing agreements with service providers who process your data that restrict and regulate their processing of your data on our behalf.
If you are in the UK, Switzerland, or the EEA and you do not consent to your data being processed by us or by our service providers in the United States,
please follow the steps outlined in the Right to delete
section above and contact us via our HelpDesk,
and please stop accessing our Sites.
8) Non Discrimination, Complaints and Disputes
All content and services offered on the Sites are free of charge and Ask Media Group will not discriminate against
any user who has exercised their rights as set forth in this privacy policy.
We commit to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information.
Inquiries,
concerns or complaints may be submitted to us here.
We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about your privacy.
If, however, you believe that we have not satisfactorily addressed your complaint or concern, you may have the right
to make a complaint to the data protection authority of your state of residence. AMG is further subject to the investigatory
and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) in the United States.
9) Data Retention and Security
We have designed our Browser ID system so that we can manage our Sites while collecting as little information about
our users as possible. We retain the information tied to your Browser ID for as long as necessary to fulfill the
purpose we collected it for and for the purpose of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. To
determine the appropriate retention period for personal information we process, we consider the amount, nature, and
sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your
information, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through
other means, and the applicable legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
If you subscribe to one of our Sites’ email communications and provide us your email address, we will keep your email
address for as long as you open our email communications and six months after your email address becomes
unresponsive to our emails or when you unsubscribe.
We retain information in our HelpDesk system for up to three
years to respond to discovery requests in the event of litigation or have the ability to defend legal claims.
We retain information you provide to apply for jobs at Ask Media group for as long as we have an ongoing legitimate
business need to do so (for example, to contact you if we have a job opening that fits your qualification, or to
comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements) after which our service provider Greenhouse will
either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been
stored in backup archives), then they will securely store your information and isolate it from any further
processing until deletion is possible.
We take the security of your information seriously and use appropriate technical and organizational measures to
protect your information against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or
damage. We also limit access to information about you to employees who reasonably need access to it to provide
products or services to you, or in order to do their jobs. However, because no security system can be 100%
effective, we cannot completely guarantee the security of any information we may have collected from or about you.
10) Updates to this Privacy Policy and Contact Information
We will continue to evaluate this Privacy Policy against new technologies, applicable laws, business practices, and
our user’s needs, and may make changes accordingly. Please check this page periodically for updates. If we make any
material changes, we will post the updated Privacy Policy on this page, along with its effective date, and notify
you by means of a notice on the Sites. Except in connection with updates that materially change the ways in which we
process your information, your continued use of the Services after this Privacy Policy has been updated means that
you agree to be bound by such updates. We will provide notice in advance of the effective date with regard to any
updates that materially change the ways in which we process your personal information.
If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or the manner in which your information is processed
(or if you are an EEA resident, how your data is transferred outside of the EEA), or if you would like to submit a
request to us, please contact our Data Protection Officer here or via mail at:
Ask Media Group, LLC
Data Protection Officer
555 12th Street, Suite 300
Oakland, CA 94607
